<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fastq on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/tags/fastq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fastq on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/tags/fastq/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate FastQC Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/aggregate-fastqc-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/aggregate-fastqc-reports/</guid>
      <description>Update: MultiQC (2019-06-21) After I originally published this script for aggregating FASTQC reports, MultiQC was published by Phil Ewels. MultiQC aggregates quality-control and other associated data from sequencing tools into an interactive report. Instead of the script below, you can simply run:
# Run this command where your *_fastqc.zip files are multiqc . This will output a repor that looks like this:
Publication
 MultiQC: Summarize analysis results for multiple tools and samples in a single report  Philip Ewels, Måns Magnusson, Sverker Lundin and Max Käller  Bioinformatics (2016)  doi: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From SRA Project to FASTQ</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/from-sra-project-to-fastq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/from-sra-project-to-fastq/</guid>
      <description>Original Post (2014-10-25) The Sequence Read Archive (SRA) contains sequence data from scientific studies stored in a special ‘sra’ format. Data is stored in a hierarchical format:
Project ▸ Study ▸ Sample ▸ Experiment ▸ Run
Recently, I had to use the SRA to download all of the sequence data for a given project. This required querying the SRA database for all the runs in a sequencing project and converting them to FASTQs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Double Checking FASTQs</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/double-checking-fastqs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/double-checking-fastqs/</guid>
      <description>When you have performed a sequencing project, quality control is one of the first things you will need to do. Unfortunately, sample mix-ups and other issues can and do happen. Systematic biases can also occur by machine and lane.
This script will extracting basic information from a set of FASTQs and output it to summary file (fastq_summary.txt). This will work with demultiplexed FASTQs generated by Illumina machines that appear in the following format:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>