<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pubmed on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/tags/pubmed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pubmed on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/tags/pubmed/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Pairwise Queries in R</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/visualizing-pairwise-queries-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/visualizing-pairwise-queries-in-r/</guid>
      <description>You can look for interesting associations between sets of search terms on PubMed by comparing how often two terms co-occur. The code below returns the number of publications where both terms are mentioned, acting as a rough estimate for how associated they are (at least, in the scholarly world).
In the example below, I show the results from organisms x diseases/disease-associated terms which is an imperfect look at how various terms estimate of how much each disease is studied in a given organism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Google Sheets to identify gene-disease associations in Pubmed</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/use-google-sheets-to-identify-gene-disease-associations-in-pubmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/use-google-sheets-to-identify-gene-disease-associations-in-pubmed/</guid>
      <description>Google Docs allows you to import XML. By using NCBIs esearch service, you can query pubmed for a list of genes. Stick the following code in A2, and a keyword in B2:
=importXML(&amp;#34;http://eutils.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/eutils/esearch.fcgi?db=pubmed&amp;amp;term=&amp;#34; &amp;amp; B2 ,&amp;#34;(//Count)[1]&amp;#34;) What is more valuable, however, is if given a gene list – you can query pubmed for each gene combined with a second keyword like a disease.
For example, suppose you are studying Cleft lip and Palate and are left with a set of genes identified from a gene expression analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>