<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bash on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/tags/bash/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bash on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:26:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/tags/bash/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A bash alias for Microsoft Excel (Mac only)</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/a-bash-alias-for-microsoft-excel-mac-only/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:26:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/a-bash-alias-for-microsoft-excel-mac-only/</guid>
      <description>Years ago I wrote a function for opening excel from R. While I would never use Excel for data analysis, it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good for sorting and browsing data. Thats why I wrote a simple bash alias for opening up text documents from the terminal.
function excel() { tmp=`mktemp` out=${1} cat ${out} &amp;gt; $tmp open -a &amp;#34;Microsoft Excel&amp;#34; $tmp }</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log commands to Google Cloud Stackdriver Logs</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/log-commands-to-google-cloud-stackdriver-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/log-commands-to-google-cloud-stackdriver-logs/</guid>
      <description>Google Cloud Platform (GCP) has a service called Stackdriver logging which provides a nice interface for accessing logs.
Stackdriver logging is integrated with all GCP services but it can also be extended. Users can create custom logs and access them centrally using the web-based interface or the Google Cloud SDK.
This got me wondering whether there was a way to log terminal commands locally or on a server. It is possible by setting the PROMPT_COMMAND variable in BASH.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rename Samples within a VCF/BCF</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/rename-samples-within-a-vcf/bcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/rename-samples-within-a-vcf/bcf/</guid>
      <description>Update: Use bcftools (2019-06-21) Since this post was originally written, bcftools has added a command for renaming samples called reheader which allows sample names to be easily modified.
Original Post (2014-12-05) These two simple bash functions make it easy to rename samples within a bcf file by using the filename given (if it is a single sample file) or adding a prefix to all samples. This is useful if you want to merge bcf files where the sample names are identical in both (for comparison purposes).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>