<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bam on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/tags/bam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in bam on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 01:15:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/tags/bam/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Parallelize by iterating over chromosomal ranges</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/parallelize-by-iterating-over-chromosomal-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 01:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/parallelize-by-iterating-over-chromosomal-ranges/</guid>
      <description>I have added a new utility to seq-collection called iter which generates chromosomal ranges. Lists of genomic ranges can be easily plugged into utilities such as xargs or gnu-parallel to parallelize commands.
For example:
sc iter test.bam 100,000 # Iterate on bins of 100k base pairs # Outputs &amp;gt; I:0-999999 &amp;gt; I:1000000-1999999 &amp;gt; I:2000000-2999999 &amp;gt; I:3000000-3999999 &amp;gt; I:4000000-4999999 Note:BAMs use a 0-based coordinate system; VCFs are 1-basedThis list of genomic ranges can be used to process a BAM or VCF in parallel:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aggregate FastQC Reports</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/aggregate-fastqc-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/aggregate-fastqc-reports/</guid>
      <description>Update: MultiQC (2019-06-21) After I originally published this script for aggregating FASTQC reports, MultiQC was published by Phil Ewels. MultiQC aggregates quality-control and other associated data from sequencing tools into an interactive report. Instead of the script below, you can simply run:
# Run this command where your *_fastqc.zip files are multiqc . This will output a repor that looks like this:
Publication
 MultiQC: Summarize analysis results for multiple tools and samples in a single report Philip Ewels, Måns Magnusson, Sverker Lundin and Max Käller Bioinformatics (2016) doi: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculate Depth and Breadth of Coverage From a bam File</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/calculate-depth-and-breadth-of-coverage-from-a-bam-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/calculate-depth-and-breadth-of-coverage-from-a-bam-file/</guid>
      <description>Original Post What is the difference between depth and coverage in sequencing experiments? Actually – they refer to the same thing, the average number of reads aligned to an individual base. Previously, I had thought coverage referred to the percentage of the genome with aligned reads to it; however the more appropriate term for this is breadth of coverage. This paper more precisely defines what breadth of coverage and depth of coverage mean.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>