<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CYCLING on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/tags/cycling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CYCLING on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 20:26:29 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/tags/cycling/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Strava plugin for bitbar</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/a-strava-plugin-for-bitbar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 20:26:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/a-strava-plugin-for-bitbar/</guid>
      <description>Bitbar is a cool little app for MacOS that allows you to run tiny programs that display useful information in the menu bar. These can be anything from current weather conditions, to information about digital ocean droplets, or a timer application. Being that I am also a big fan of strava, I decided to put together a strava plugin for bitbar.
Wish I could put up some more impressive numbers here!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short tour around Lake Michigan</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/a-short-tour-around-lake-michigan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/a-short-tour-around-lake-michigan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve given bicycle touring a try. Originally I wanted to bike around Lake Michigan, but it turns out to be over &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lake_Michigan&#34;&gt;1,400 miles&lt;/a&gt;. So I compromised on a three day trip around a good chunk and making use of the ferry from Muskeegon, MI to Milwaukee, WI. This was my first time &amp;#8211; so I also decided to stay in hotels. Next time I intend to camp. I learned a few valuable lessons along the way!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pack less stuff!&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; I had way too much. In fact, I wound up breaking two spokes on the second day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shorten the days&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; Having never gone more than 40 miles in a single day, I decided to go 108 on the first day. Yeah. I probably should have gone more like 60-70 each day. By the time I got to my destination each day I was too tired to do anything. Part of the experience is seeing new places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a proper touring bike&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8211; I didn&amp;#8217;t use a touring bike because I don&amp;#8217;t have one (yet). I used a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trekbikes.com/us/en/bikes/town/fitness/fx/7_2_fx_wsd_2014/#&#34;&gt;Trek 7.2&lt;/a&gt;. My wrists hurt a lot for parts of the trip. Next time I&amp;#8217;ll get a proper touring bike with the appropriate handle bars.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;text-center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.danielecook.com/Screen-Shot-2014-07-12-at-7.27.56-PM1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Trip around Lake Michigan&#34;  class=&#34;thumbnail&#34; style=&#34;margin:auto;&#34; /&gt;&lt;small style=&#34;color:#4792f3&#34;&gt;Day 1&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span style=&#34;color:Red&#34;&gt;Day 2&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span style=&#34;color:#fba43c&#34;&gt;Ferry&lt;/span&gt; · &lt;span style=&#34;color:Green&#34;&gt;Day 3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pictures&#34;&gt;Pictures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.danielecook.com/IMG_0826.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Michigan&#34;  class=&#34;caption&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.danielecook.com/IMG_0849.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Outside Muskeegan&#34;  class=&#34;caption&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to plot all of your Runkeeper Data</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/how-to-plot-all-of-your-runkeeper-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/how-to-plot-all-of-your-runkeeper-data/</guid>
      <description>Runs in Iowa City  Running and Biking in Chicago   If you use runkeeper and pay for a yearly subscription (runkeeper elite), you can export your data and plot all of your activities simultaneously using R. I&amp;#8217;ve written a script for doing so (Special thanks to flowing data which has a tutorial that helped with a few key parts of this).
The script does a few unique things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I Run and Bike in Chicago</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/where-i-run-and-bike-in-chicago/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/where-i-run-and-bike-in-chicago/</guid>
      <description>Original Post (2014-05-25) Using runkeeper and with the help of a tutorial at flowing data, I was able to plot all of the running and biking I&amp;#8217;ve been doing in Chicago since moving here two years ago. The blue is running and the black is biking.
 Update: Strava (2019-06-21) I have since migrated my data to Strava - which I like a lot better than runkeeper. You can migrate your data using the Tapariik service.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>