<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/projects/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker News Trending</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/hntrending/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/hntrending/</guid>
      <description>Hacker News is a great source of tech-news. However, the site has a very high turnover rate in terms of stories. If you do not check it daily it is easy to miss something.
That is why I created Hacker News Trending (HN Trending). HN Trending is a simple website that aggregates Hacker news stories by popularity over the past week, month, year, and over all time. HN Trending is updated every Sunday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IEX API Python</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/iex-api-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/iex-api-python/</guid>
      <description>IEX-API-Python is a python wrapper for the IEX API. IEX-API-Python can be used to retrieve financial data such as stock prices, news, or company information from IEX. Data can be obtained as JSON or converted into Pandas DataFrames.
IEX is an exchange founded by Brad Katsuyama and written about in the book Flash Boys by Michael Lewis.
 GitHub Documentation  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upvote.pub</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/upvote.pub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/upvote.pub/</guid>
      <description>Upvote.pub (https://www.upvote.pub) was a shortlived experiment to create a reddit-style clone specifically for scientific publications. Users could submit scientific publications from arXiv, bioRxiv, PubMed, or using a DOI. These submissions could then be upvoted or discussed using a commenting function (which also featured upvotes). I created the site because I like HackerNews and reddit, and I believe more dialogue regarding scientific publications would be a great thing.
The site made the front page of HackerNews and drew mixed criticims.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCF-Kit</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/vcf-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/vcf-kit/</guid>
      <description>Abstract
The variant call format (VCF) is a popular standard for storing genetic variation data. As a result, a large collection of tools has been developed that perform diverse analyses using VCF files. However, some tasks common to statistical and population geneticists have not been created yet. To streamline these types of analyses, we created novel tools that analyze or annotate VCF files and organized these tools into a command-line based utility named VCF-kit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>elegansvariation.org</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/elegansvariation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/elegansvariation/</guid>
      <description>The C. elegans Natural Diversity Resource (CeNDR) is scientific web application that enables users to perform genetic studies. The web application is deployed using Google Cloud Platform and is written using Flask, a python-based web framework.
The site features a genome-browser, a catalog for ordering scientific specimens, a download portal, and can also launch analytical pipelines for performing analyses. CeNDR is actively used by the scientific community and has become a valuable tool for performing studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source Contributions</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 1987 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/open-source/</guid>
      <description>These are open-source projects that I have contributed to, but did not initiate.
 mosdepth - [nim]; Helped develop summary stats of coverage data. memoise - [R]; Developed cloud-based memoisation on aws.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini-Projects</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/mini-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 1987 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/projects/mini-projects/</guid>
      <description>I have also developed a few utilities / tools you may find useful.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>