<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alfred on Daniel E. Cook</title>
    <link>https://www.danielecook.com/tags/alfred/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alfred on Daniel E. Cook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.danielecook.com/tags/alfred/feed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred Image Utilities</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/alfred-image-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/alfred-image-utilities/</guid>
      <description>A workflow for making quick changes to image files. Alfred-image-utilities grabs any selected images in the frontmost finder window and can apply changes to them. Most of the time a copy of the image is made and its extension is changed to &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;.orig.&amp;lt;ext&amp;gt;. You can replace the original file by holding command when executing most commands.
Download Main Menu
Convert to png or jpg
You can convert from a large number of formats to these jpg or png.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quiver-alfred</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/quiver-alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/quiver-alfred/</guid>
      <description>Search Quiver from Alfred! Quiver-alfred quickly constructs a database of your notes for fast and easy querying.
Download Usage Type qset to set your quiver library location. Quiver-Alfred constructs a database of your notes to make querying as fast as possible. The database should refresh once every hour and should only take a few seconds to create.
Type q to use!
You can search tags by hitting q #.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alfred workflow for generating markdown tables from your clipboard</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-generating-markdown-tables-from-your-clipboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-generating-markdown-tables-from-your-clipboard/</guid>
      <description>Generate markdown tables from clipboard content.
Download Usage Copy a csv or tsv. The script will attempt to intelligently guess the format. For example, if you copy the table below:
carat cut color clarity depth table price x y z 0.23 Ideal E SI2 61.5 55 326 3.95 3.98 2.43 0.21 Premium E SI1 59.8 61 326 3.89 3.84 2.31 0.23 Good E VS1 56.9 65 327 4.05 4.07 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alfred Workflow for Wormbase</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-wormbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-wormbase/</guid>
      <description>I have created an Alfred workflow for looking up gene information in wormbase. You can search by wormbase ID (e.g., WBGene00006759) You can use it to search for genes. Returned results will include:
 Gene identifiers Location Caenorhabditis orthologs Publications  Download the latest version Usage Search for Genes
Get Gene Information</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Alfred Workflow for Codebox</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-codebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-codebox/</guid>
      <description>[Codebox]() is a great program for storing and accessing snippets. It offers a quickbar menu item, but I thought Alfred might offer more functionality. So I wrote a workflow for it.
Download Codebox-Alfred workflow Important! The workflow works fairly well, but there are a few caveats. You should not do the following with your codebox libraries:
 Don&amp;#8217;t put spaces into tag, list, or folder names. Use an underscore instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HGNC Search: Instant search of human genes with Alfred</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/hgnc-search-instant-search-of-human-genes-with-alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/hgnc-search-instant-search-of-human-genes-with-alfred/</guid>
      <description>I have put together an Alfred workflow &amp;#8211; this one searches the HGNC database for genes! I have converted the text database from the HGNC website and configured it for full text search using sqlite. This allows you to lookup genes by their UCSC, Entrez, Vega, Ensembl, and many other identifiers very quickly.
Download the latest release Usage Full text search of the HGNC database
Information and links are provided for individual genes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An alfred workflow for working with sequence data</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-working-with-sequence-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/an-alfred-workflow-for-working-with-sequence-data/</guid>
      <description> I&amp;rsquo;ve put together a simple alfred workflow with a few utilities for working with sequence data.
Download the latest release of Seq-Utilities
Usage Generate a random dna sequence 200 base pairs long.
Generate the complement, reverse complement, RNA, and protein of a DNA sequence
Open up blast and pre-populate the search field
blast ATGTCCTCGTTCGACCGTCGTATTGAAGCTGCATGTAAA  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alfred Workflow for Creating a Data Analysis Project</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/alfred-workflow-for-creating-a-data-analysis-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/alfred-workflow-for-creating-a-data-analysis-project/</guid>
      <description>This idea I got from my brother. The idea is to keep any data analysis/bioinformatic projects I work on organized by sticking to a standard template. I wrote an Alfred Workflow for generating the template. There are a couple key features:
Directory Structure
 Markdown (md) extension &amp;#8211; is used for the readme because its simple and so that the directory is ready for github if desired. Data Folder &amp;#8211; This directory is used for storing raw data and scripts that are used to clean and prepare data for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create New File in Finder with Alfred 2</title>
      <link>https://www.danielecook.com/create-new-file-in-finder-with-alfred-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2013 22:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.danielecook.com/create-new-file-in-finder-with-alfred-2/</guid>
      <description>I have created a simple workflow for Alfred 2 which makes it easy to create a new text file in the frontmost finder window. Update &amp;#8211; at the suggestion of a visitor &amp;#8211; James Kachan &amp;#8211; I have updated the workflow to automatically open the new file in a text editor. An alternative, more advanced workflow for Alfred 2 has also been created by Ian Isted.
Usage Open Alfred 2, and type new followed by the name of the file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>